cogeco.ca 2001-04-05

# COGECO: PRIVACY PROTECTION POLICY OF COGECO

**PRIVACY PROTECTION POLICY OF COGECO**

  1. Protection of privacy is important at COGECO Inc. To this end, COGECO has adopted the following policy, which applies also to its subsidiaries COGECO Cable Inc. and COGECO Radio-Television Inc. and to their direct and indirect operating subsidiaries, all collectively referred to as COGECO for the purposes of this policy.
  2. Protection of privacy requires that the collection, use, disclosure and retention of personal information satisfy the requirements of the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ (Canada), which will come into force on January 1st, 2001. COGECO supports the principles of this Act and abides by it.
  3. Personal information means information about an identifiable individual.
  4. COGECO collects personal information as part of its activities only for the following purposes :
    1. Establish, develop and preserve its business relationship respectively with its customers, its employees and other individuals with whom it deals; 
    2. Provide the products or services that it offers, or receive the products or services that it requests, and ensure that all related transactions are supported and implemented; 
    3. Understand and assess the interests, wants and needs of customers with a view to improving products and services already offered, or to offer new products and services; 
    4. Manage its businesses and ensure the efficiency, reliability and security of its systems; and 
    5. Fulfill its obligations resulting from the law. 

  5. COGECO does not provide or sell personal information to third parties for commercial or solicitation purposes.
  6. Personal information collected by COGECO may include, as needed, information with a view to establishing or verifying the credit of persons that use, or intend to use, one or more of the products or services offered by COGECO. For this purpose, COGECO may obtain or share credit information on a confidential basis from or with credit evaluation organizations.
  7. COGECO may, as needed, share personal information on a confidential basis with its authorized representatives, dealers, retailers, contractors and agents.
  8. COGECO may share personal information as between its various related entities and businesses in order to avoid duplication, promote security, or increase the efficiency or quality of information systems, or otherwise to develop product or service offerings that are more interesting or relevant to the customers.
  9. COGECO obtains consent of the individuals concerned for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information through various means, including individual or collective agreements, forms, welcome kits, bills, or printed or electronic communications.
  10. COGECO must obtain consent with respect to the collection, use or disclosure of personal information of a person for any purpose other than the purposes identified in this policy.
  11. COGECO retains personal information only for the period of time required to fulfill the purposes that it has identified with respect to such information. COGECO will render anonymous, erase or destroy personal information that is no longer required for such purposes.
  12. COGECO applies, for itself and in its relations with the persons or organizations with whom it deals, procedures, practices and measures with a view to ensuring that personal information in its possession or control are adequately protected.
  13. COGECO ensures that personal information that it collects is accurate, complete and up-to-date.
  14. COGECO Cable Inc. and COGECO Radio-Television Inc. are respectively members of the Canadian Cable Television Association (CCTA) and The Canadian Association of Broadcasters (CAB), which also support and promote the protection of privacy. Persons wishing to obtain more information in this regard may do so by communicating directly at the following addresses : Canadian Cable Television Association  
1010-360, Albert Street  
Ottawa Ontario  
K1R 7X7  
Tél. : (613) 232-2631  
Télécopieur : (613) 232-2137  

The Canadian Association of Broadcasters  
P.O. Box 627, Station B  
306-350, Sparks Street  
Ottawa (Ontario)  
K1P 5S2  
Tél. : (613) 233-4035  
Télécopieur : (613) 233-6961  

  15. Persons wishing to obtain further information on this policy or on the personal information that concerns them, to have access to such personal information, or to file a complaint in this regard, may do so to the designated privacy persons at the addresses stated below :
    1. For COGECO Cable in Ontario :  
David Vanden Bosch  
Privacy Co-ordinator, Cable Ontario  
950 Syscon Road  
P.O. Box 5076, Station Main  
Burlington, Ontario  
L7R 4S6
    2. For COGECO Cable in Québec :  
Lise Crochetière  
Privacy Co-ordinator, Cable Québec  
1630, 6e Rue  
Trois-Rivières (Québec)  
G8Y 5B8
    3. For COGECO Radio-Television :  
Monique Lacharité  
Privacy Co-ordinator  
2830, boulevard St-Martin Est, Suite 200  
Laval (Québec)  
H7E 5A1
  16. Persons wishing to obtain further information on the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ (Canada) or on their rights under this Act may contact the Privacy Commissioner at the [privcan@fox.nstn.ca](mailto:privcan@fox.nstn.ca) address or by calling at 1-800-282-1376.
